Krishnan Shankar



krishnans2006@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/krishnan-shankar



https://github.com/KrishnanS2006

Summary

I am a High School Freshman specializing in Full-Stack Web Development. I mainly use Python, integrated with Flask, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Firebase, and/or SQL, to create fully-functioning web applications. I am also skilled in advanced Pygame, and I have built multiple Discord Bots using Discord.py. In addition to Python, I am also skilled in Java and can program classes and Java Swing GUIs. Finally, I have experience using Linux (Ubuntu, Arch Linux, and Debian on a Raspberry Pi), Git and GitHub, and deploying using Heroku or AWS Elastic Beanstalk.

Experience



System Administrator

Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology

Jun 2021 - Present (5 months +)

The Student Systems Administrators are a group of students who maintain computer equipment and networked services in TJ's Computer Systems Lab (CSL). We run services which power the entire school's operations, including TJ Email accounts and a student-run and developed project known as the TJ Intranet, used daily by students and staff, which manages the Eighth Period student activity program. Sysadmins manage over 30 physical servers and 60 student workstations, all powered by GNU/Linux and open source software.

Computer Programmer

TJUAV

Feb 2021 - Present (9 months +)

TJUAV is TJ High School's Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) Team. We participate in the annual AUVSI SUAS competition, where we compete with an Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) against colleges from around the world. In 2019, TJUAV placed 23rd overall out of over 75 college teams (auvsi-suas.org for more information). Working on the airframe, designing electrical systems, engineering a ground vehicle, developing an autopilot system, transmitting data with an aircraft, and autonomously classifying images are common tasks.



Corporate Sponsorship Coordinator

HackTJ

Jun 2021 - Present (5 months +)

HackTJ brings together 500 of the brightest students on the East Coast to TJ's own student hackathon. Here, high school students learn how to build their own apps and websites in just 24 hours! As part of the HackTJ Team, I am responsible for updating and maintaining the official website of HackTJ (hacktj.org), along with judging projects and coordinating with sponsors.



Technical Lead

HackAlphaX

Dec 2020 - Present (11 months +)

As the Technical Lead of HackAlphaX, I am responsible for updating and maintaining the official site (hackalphax.co) and all other technology used to help ensure NextStep Hacks runs smoothly.

Operations Lead

HackAlphaX

Dec 2020 - Present (11 months +)

As the Operations Lead of HackAlphaX, I handle the operations before, during, and after the hackathon, by making sure everything runs smoothly. I am also the Point-of-Contact of the HackAlphaX Executive Team during the Hackathon, for any rules clarifications or questions.

Labs Intern at CodeDay

CodeDay

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

DigiChef is a website to help you find what you would like to cook, and publish your recipes in a simple and effective way! DigiChef's goal is for its users to discover new recipes without the extra filler. The frontend of DigiChef is created using React and Material-UI. The backend uses Django REST Framework and a PostgreSQL Database to provide a JSON API for the frontend to use. Both the frontend and the backend are hosted as a Docker Container using AWS.

Education



Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology

High School Diploma, Computer Science Aug 2020 - Jun 2024

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Flask • Discord API • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Firebase • Cloud Firestore • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • AWS Elastic Beanstalk